[Forging Justice]
[Episode 20]
Mei.
Qian Xingliang is here.
Will you go meet him?
[Meeting Room 1]
Please... have a seat.
I'm fine squatting.
No, please sit.
We'll talk after you're seated.
Just sit down.
Come on.
Mr. Qian,
I am truly sorry about
what happened years ago.
But at that time,
we didn't have a better choice.
After all, investigative capabilities
and the general understanding
back then were vastly different
from today.
That said,
on all accounts,
you still suffered
a great deal of harm.
On my own behalf,
I'd like to apologize to you.
It's okay. It's nothing.
Nothing.
Judges, if this is
the attitude you take,
our discussion will be smooth then.
Please sit.
Yes, be seated.
My client
was kept behind bars for a total
of 2,941 days.
During this period,
his home was smashed
by Yu Sanhua's family multiple times.
Right? And his mother
passed away out of grief
and indignation caused by all this.
Who do you think should be responsible
for his losses?
You're suggesting...
I, as Mr. Qian's
representive,
will formally file for state compensation.
Mr. Tan,
the State Compensation Law
has just been enacted.
None of us are sure
about its implementation.
Could you please offer
more specifics?
For example, you demand one million here.
-On what ground?
-One million?
That's too much. Too much.
Did I say you could speak?
Tan Xin,
how can you treat him like that?
How do I treat him now?
Don't you remember how you defended him
years ago?
How do you have the nerve
to shut him up now?
No matter how I defended him back then,
you would've sentenced him
to death anyway,
right?
Even if Yuan Yifang had represented him,
would there have been any difference?
I'm warning you,
take our demands
seriously.
Otherwise,
we will raise funds publicly.
Let's see who will be
a national disgrace then.
Let's go.
Thank you, officers.
Wait, why did you thank them?
Would you have been imprisoned
if it weren't for them?
Let's go.
I shouldn't have apologized.
That lawyer has seized on
some words I said.
He'll definitely use them against us.
Whoever does wrong should apologize.
It's only right.
We can't stop
a lightning strike,
but we shouldn't run toward it.
Mei,
Qian Xingliang spent 8 years in prison.
His life is ruined.
Did you not see that?
I did see that.
But what does it have to do with us?
The decision wasn't made by us.
Think whatever you want.
But I can never bring myself
to say "it has nothing to do with me."
Justice Blooming in a Corner—
a record of Binjiang Intermediate Court's
Judge Xia Yingjie
clearing a wrongful conviction.
How's my writing?
Am I rusty now?
Over these past few years,
judgements are all I've been writing.
Tell me what you think
of my work.
Hey, what do you mean by this?
What are you getting at?
A serious incident happened.
I'm the one getting the credit now?
Yes, and no, in a sense.
Now, the court needs to set up
a positive example
to tell everyone
that in the Intermediate Court,
besides judges like Mei Fang
who are eager for quick success,
there are still judges
like you, Xia Yingjie,
who strictly uphold justice.
Mei Fang and I were
on a collegial panel.
At that time,
I didn't stick to my opinion till the end.
I chose to make a concession.
So I should bear
the responsibility with her.
W-What's the point
of writing this?
Can you stop being
so emotionally involved?
If you take my advice,
you can completely extricate yourself
from this matter,
and receive far more commendation
than you could imagine.
Thank you for looking out for me.
Do you remember we teamed up
for a moot court
competition
in our sophomore year?
I remember.
We lost to Yizhong and got second place.
It was our first time
getting a certificate.
We both got drunk
on the day of the award ceremony.
I couldn't believe I worked so hard
only to get second place.
While drinking, I cried and puked.
It was you who stayed up all night
to draw a first-prize certificate
for me.
Even the official seal looked so real.
At that time, I made up my mind
that in the future, I must
win a genuine
first prize.
That's why you truly deserve
the credit this time.
No.
This time is just like before.
You've drawn me another prize certificate.
This is also a fake.
You are too hard on yourself,
Xia Yingjie.
Chief Judge Yu, please believe me.
I'm not afraid of being held accountable.
I'm ready to be punished
for my past indecision.
Also, I implore you
to allow me to win fair and square.
Okay?
Xia,
Chief Judge Yu
told us to write a report.
Should I write it or you?
You should write it.
Is it appropriate...
for me to write it?
You were the presiding judge back then.
That's exactly why I hesitate.
I'm worried that if I write it,
they'll say I'm glossing over
the real issues.
You should do it instead.
Fine, I'll write it then.
But you must not admit
that it was our fault.
In fact, it was never
our fault.
Whether to sentence him
to death or death with reprieve
was decided by the higher-ups.
It really had nothing to do with us.
Mei,
if I'm writing this,
I won't try to defend myself.
I'll accept any punishment.
Wait, Xia Yingjie.
What do you mean by that?
So you get to play the saint,
while I take the fall, huh?
You'll accept any punishment?
I was the presiding judge.
Will you be the one to get punished?
If there's punishment,
I'll be the first one to take it!
Mei,
don't get it wrong.
We were on a collegial panel.
The two of us delivered the verdict
of the case together.
If there's liability,
it'll be ours.
I swear to share the woes with you.
Tian Mingyuan.
Here.
Ren Xiaojun.
Yan Jicai.
Here!
Jin Jian.
Here.
Hao Xuefeng.
Here!
Wu Lidong.
Here.
Yi Dayong.
Here!
Human tissue was found
under 8 of the victim's fingernails.
It proves that the victim struggled
with someone before her death.
Does the DNA match
Yan Jicai's?
No, it doesn't.
What does the file say?
The file says
such human tissue
is not relevant to the case.
Yan Jicai's counsel mentioned
that it was not until the fourth day
after the incident that Yan was arrested.
No injuries were found on his body
during the physical examination,
not even a single scratch.
Did the victim not resist
before she died?
If not,
why were there skin flakes
under her nails?
And such human tissue
doesn't belong to Yan Jicai.
Listen to this...
Mentor, won't you say
it's a logical paradox?
How did
the police explain it?
They believed
that Yan Jicai launched a sudden attack.
The girl was caught off guard.
Losing the ability to resist in an instant
often causes
obvious or severe
physical injuries.
Unless the killer is a real professional
who knows human anatomy
and masters certain methods.
Does Yan Jicai have that kind of ability?
The autopsy report says
the girl was strangled to death.
There are no signs
of severe blows to her head.
What else?
The time.
Yan Jicai couldn't have possibly done
the crime at the time
stated in his confession.
This can be deduced from the time shown
on the surveillance video.
For such a heinous rape and murder case,
the court only gave Yan
a death sentence with reprieve.
That's a message itself.
A judgment that leaves room for doubt.
Yes.
Just another
judgment that leaves room for doubt.
Mentor, I think...
Yan Jicai might really have been
wrongfully convicted.
Wrongfully convicted?
Then tell me who the real killer is.
[Details revealed about the necrophilic
murder by Jia Peng the taxi driver]
Is what says in this report
true?
How about I go look into it?
No!
Let me do it.
I plan to read these files
a few more times
and sort out
all the suspicious points for you
before I leave.
No need for that.
Just leave already. Go!
I'm not leaving.
I'll bug you nonstop.
Xia,
a wrongful conviction was made after all.
The court leaders,
including me,
have all actively taken responsibility.
I'll accept whatever
punishment.
You'll be given
a major administrative demerit,
removed from the Intermediate Court,
and assigned to a grassroots court
for experience.
What about Judge Mei?
I'm afraid she'll have to
leave the ranks of judges.
Court President,
can she be also transferred
to a grassroots court like I am?
Please give her a second chance.
Xia,
the public security bureau has put
3 of the police officers
who handled the case back then
in criminal detention.
Deputy Court Pres. Yu told me
about your stance on this matter.
Deputy Court Pres. Yu?
The designation is yet to be announced.
But the matter wouldn't have been resolved
so smoothly without him.
I know you must feel wronged.
In one year
or two at most,
I hope you will still return to working
in the Intermediate Court.
Thank you, Court President.
Thanks to Deputy Court Pres. Yu too.
Oh, right.
If it's not too much trouble for you,
have a talk with Mei Fang.
Okay.
When I spoke to her,
she showed a slightly weird attitude.
Mei values her job a lot.
She must be very upset
and needs time to process it.
No, no. It was exactly the opposite.
When I was talking to her,
she kept smiling.
It gave me the creeps.
Xia, make yourself at home.
H-Help yourself to some water.
My hands are full now.
No, please, Mei.
You really can't let me sit idle.
Or I might end up tearing
your house down.
L-Let me help you with something.
Then do you know how to chop vegetables?
Chop those green peppers for me.
I've washed them already.
Okay, got it.
How very odd.
At first,
I was really scared.
I felt like
the sky was falling.
But after talking to the Court President,
even to my own surprise,
the heavy burden in my heart
was lifted.
A new chapter in my life just began.
Why was that?
Maybe deep down,
I've already
long hated being a judge.
You don't want to be a judge?
Why?
I don't like it, and I'm not good at it.
I just wanted to
prove myself to my late husband.
Actually, over these years,
that drive
has long been gone.
You can drink a bit, huh?
Yes.
Come on, let's have a drink.
Here you are.
Thanks.
Come on, cheers.
Sure.
Dig in.
However, I still
feel sorry for you.
Xia.
You know what?
After my husband passed,
I felt like my life was over too.
I had no life of my own,
or happiness of my own.
It was like I spent the past ten-odd years
carrying his dead body on my back.
But now, all is fine.
My career is over,
and I am relieved.
Somebody made that decision for me.
Mei,
easy on the drinks.
It's okay.
I really am fine.
Actually, I'm quite pleased.
I've decided
to leave this city
and put the past behind.
I'm going to clear my late husband
out of my life.
Xia,
in fact, I feel
sorry for you.
You shouldn't have made such a sacrifice
and taken the responsibility
that was not supposed to be yours at all.
I pleaded with the Court President
for you.
But he declined.
Thank you, Mei.
However,
these are the consequences I should bear.
For what it's worth,
moving on from the past,
finding new life goals,
and charting a new course for yourself
matter more than anything else.
I'm happy for you!
Yes.
That's also what I think.
I really owe you a thank you.
Actually, it was you
who changed my mind.
I even bought sleeping pills.
After my husband's passing,
I thought no one in the rest
of my life would ever say
what you said to me.
"I swear to share the woes with you."
Although you failed to exonerate
Qian Xingliang,
you did save me.
You are a good judge.
Come on.
Keep up the good work.
Be a good judge.
Xia.
I will.
Keep it up.
I definitely will.
-Cheers.
Leave the door open.
Well,
I've talked to Court Pres. Sun
of Guding County Court.
If you meet any difficulties,
feel free to tell him anytime.
Who gave you the authority
to interfere with my work?
I no longer report to you.
Haven't you realized that?
It was Court Pres. Qiu's idea.
He was worried that you couldn't adapt
at the grassroots level,
since you're a female comrade.
It's not like I never stayed in Nanyu.
You are not assigned
to the Guding County Court,
but further down
to Dashijia Village Tribunal.
The chief judge there is an old man
surnamed Hu.
He's probably too busy
with farm work lately
to have time for you.
Yingjie, we are schoolmates,
and the only ones
who know each other best here.
So, I just meant to...
Forget it. Never mind.
I'll leave you to it.
Have I told you?
A few years ago, I paid a visit to Lihui
at Xijiang Province Bieshan Prison.
Why did you suddenly bring it up?
Compared to Bieshan,
wherever the court assigns me,
I'd see it as a privilege
and a training opportunity.
I should be grateful.
The 1979 Criminal Law
and Criminal Procedure Law,
as New China's
[National Symposium on Legal Revision]
first Criminal Law
and Criminal Procedure Law,
[Chen Yizhong]
once played a positive role
in the society
and the building of the legal system.
With the development of the times,
their limitations
have inevitably emerged.
Given that, it is our belief
that the Criminal law
and the Criminal Procedure Law
should be both overhauled.
In amending the law,
some legal concepts
should be brought light on.
Only by making up for all
the shortcomings
will the Criminal Law
and the Criminal Procedure Law
be considered relatively sound.
But we must note that the revision
has to be aligned
with China's actual conditions.
We must be cautious
and proceed step by step.
Yizhong,
the journey of amending the law
is long and rough.
What you consider
as basic concepts
are probably
beyond common sense,
challenging
the existing knowledge system,
and even absurd
and rebellious
in the eyes of some people.
Besides,
we are not saints.
What we say
may not be always correct.
Some things
make sense in theory,
but when put into practice,
they just don't work.
Any undertaking takes time.
We're revising the law,
a vital instrument for the state.
So we must be extremely prudent.
Are you here to gain experience?
No.
I'm here for making a mistake.
What kind of a mistake?
I disregarded a human life.
Just a mistake.
Alright, sit tight.
The road ahead is bumpy.
Here she comes.
She's here.
She's arriving?
Thanks for the ride.
No problem.
Sir, thanks
for your work!
No problem.
Hello.
Hello. You must be Judge Xia, right?
Yes, I am.
My name is Hu Xingwang.
I'm also a judge here.
Hello, Judge Hu.
Hello to you.
This is my wife.
Hello, Mrs. Hu.
Hello.
That's my eldest grandson.
And that's my eldest granddaughter.
Hello, ma'am!
Hello.
Let's help you settle down first.
I'll have my wife prepare
a simple meal later.
We'll make do for now.
I-I'd hate to let you
go to so much trouble.
No, not at all.
I'm not able to cook much,
but some noodles.
Come on.
Okay. I'm fine with anything.
I'll take your luggage. Let's go.
No need.
I can carry it myself.
Alright, this way.
Fair skin.
So...
fair!
Such fair skin!
What's that gibberish?
Yin Ping,
don't you mess around!
Don't be afraid.
Though he's demented,
he never hurts anyone.
Let's go.
Follow up.
Zhou and Cheng
were right.
We aren't doing what we're supposed to.
What professionals are we?
We still have to suck it all up, don't we?
You deserve it.
You are obsessed with money.
I'm tired.
Exhausted, I'd say. I want a break.
Listen,
you should quickly
get your act together
and take over Mr. Yuan's position.
Get down to some real business.
The new Criminal Procedure Law
is about to take effect.
Your win rate will be
higher, I suppose.
I know you're giving me good advice
through sarcastic remarks,
but I still won't jump on
that sinking ship.
If Mr. Yuan's today
is my tomorrow,
then I'd rather swallow my pride.
Continue to drink then.
You don't seem very tired to me.
Fine. I'll have a drink.
You called me out
in the middle of the night.
Whose life are you trying to save?
I'm getting married.
She gave me an ultimatum.
Isn't my life going to an end?
Who are you marrying?
Still that girl named...
Ding Rui?
What do you mean by "still"?
Would I dare to have her replaced?
Although Ding Zhongxiang
is about to retire,
it's still no difficult job
for him to get a gun and hunt me down
in Beijing.
If you're getting cold feet
and deciding to
be irresponsible,
then I can't help you.
Irresponsible? Help? What's that nonsense?
Y-You have to help me, though.
I'd like to invite everyone over
to Nanyu.
For what?
To help you propose marriage?
Imagine this.
Twelve years after our graduation,
while commemorating the past
and looking forward to the future,
we are holding an epoch-making
wedding of the century at the place
where our dreams began.
Hello.
Zeming.
You're holding a wedding?
Sounds great.
But I doubt if I can
attend it on that day.
Yes.
I've just been assigned to a new post.
There's a lot on my plate.
I'll make it up to you.
I'll send you a red envelope first, okay?
Yingjie works at the grassroots level now.
Completely overwhelmed.
Tell you what,
I'll call you back later.
That's bullshit!
It happened because you did a bad job
building that fence!
Even a mule could get through it!
How could you blame
that old yellow ox of mine?
You...
Defendant, watch your language.
You heartless creature!
Who are you calling heartless?
Keep your composure. Let them fight.
Let's resume the trial
when they get tired.
How's that a good idea?
It works. It's okay.
You are unreasonable!
Court adjourned!
Are you done fighting?
Enough!
No more fighting!
Xia! A phone call for you!
Coming right up!
A phone call for you!
Sit down!
This is a court. Do you know?
Hit him! Go!
Hello.
It's Chen Yizhong.
Chen Yizhong?
H-How did you figure out
this number?
I got anxious when I couldn't reach you.
So I asked Lu for your number.
You haven't given me
a single call for two years.
But suddenly, a call right now?
H-How have you been?
Are you doing okay?
I'm doing fine.
What about you?
I...
I wrote you a letter.
Oh, yes, right, I read it.
Is there a matter?
Yes.
Lu is getting married.
He hopes...
we can all attend his wedding.
Really?
He's marrying that girl...
Ding Rui, right?
I didn't expect Lu
to be this devoted.
How admirable.
Congratulations to him.
Right. H-He plans to hold
the wedding in Nanyu.
Now...
He's inviting the few of us over.
A-Are you going?
Why didn't he
call me himself?
I stopped him.
I thought I must fight for such an honor.
Cut it out.
I can't make it.
Why?
Look, Yu can't go either.
Zhang Lihui is far away.
So I'll have to go alone?
Too bad for Lu, isn't it?
Hell no.
Well...
Actually, I miss you a lot.
Oh you.
You...
How could you
bring that up
over a phone call?
You hadn't contacted her for years.
And you said you like her
on a sudden phone call?
So abrupt, wasn't it?
I didn't say I like her.
You didn't? W-What
was the point of all that?
I had it all planned out.
I meant to tell her I like her
and see if I stood a chance
after getting my doctorate.
That's only your plan, isn't it?
Do you even know
her current situation,
how she feels,
or what her plans are?
I want to go see her.
Are you quitting the important task
of revising the law?
Right now, I don't want to do anything
but go see her.
You... Then...
you must be drunk, aren't you?
You want to go see her right now?
Aren't you afraid those two old men
will skin you alive?
Besides, let me be honest with you.
You two won't last long anyway.
Long-distance relationships never work.
Aren't you in one yourself?
I...
I'm no ordinary man,
am I?
You know nothing, lad.
What?
Hey, Rui.
Yes.
I'm with Yizhong,
discussing the wedding
now.
Yes, exactly.
Keep it simple.
We'll surely keep it simple.
To comply with the changing customs,
right?
What? How many tables?
Three hundred guests?
What if the Disciplinary Committee
goes after your dad?
No.
Sorry, I was wrong.
Listen.
It hurts so bad.
I just slapped myself.
It hurts a lot. My face turned red.
It's true.
If you don't believe me,
ask Yizhong then.
Right, Yizhong?
Right?
Yes, he did.
Everyone has their match.
Let's not judge each other.
Yes, yes.
Okay.
It's all up to you, okay?
Let's do
whatever you decide.
Sure.
Mr. Lu,
sorry to keep you waiting.
Honey,
I have to go.
I'm getting busy now.
Long time no see!
Mentor.
You were absent for days.
Yes. I went back home for a few days,
sent my wife and granddaughter
back to downtown, and got them
settled.
We're in for a long battle after all.
Had better get everything together
at the base.
What long battle?
I agree with you.
This is highly likely
a wrongful conviction.
Lihui,
no prosecutor wants to see
a wrongful conviction
happen on their watch.
Also, no prosecutor hates to
overturn a wrongful conviction
with their own hands.
I want to overturn this one.
Okay. I'll be with you on it.
How naive!
Do you know how much effort
and time it takes
to overturn a conviction?
I can afford it. But can you?
You're too young.
Of course I can.
I must join you in it.
Don't argue with me!
I'm almost 60 years old.
I've spent half my life
in this godforsaken place.
I'll be retiring soon.
I don't want to end up
accomplishing nothing.
I made all these arrangements
just to force you to leave.
Tomorrow,
you must leave!
What now?
Mentor.
I... I can't
bring myself to leave.
In my heart,
you've always been
a father figure to me.
I grew up without family.
I don't even know
what my father looks like.
If asked what a father
should be like,
I'd say you.
I refuse to leave
definitely not because of that case,
but because I want to stick with you.
I can't desert you
here.
Sorry.
Fine then. I'll leave tomorrow.
I know
you're able to
overturn the conviction on your own.
I believe in you.
Let's go.
Can you give me a moment?
Okay.
Sure.
Thank you.
Lihui!
Lihui.
Slow down.
I'm fine.
Mentor, Yan Jicai
is emotionally unstable.
When you talk to him again,
try to be careful.
Plus, don't forget to take
your hypertensive drugs.
Got it.
Your coughing hasn't
gotten any better.
You should have
a proper checkup at some time.
Alright.
I'm leaving now.
Lihui!
I just submitted a report,
saying there's no substitution yet,
so you have to stay a longer while.
If they pressure you,
just say it's my fault.
Really?
Really.
You sure?
I'm absolutely sure.
You crooked old man,
why not tell me earlier?
It hurts!
Get my luggage back!
-I will!
-You go do it!
What does this mean?
I came for nothing then.
A trip in vain. No big deal.
Come on, hand it to me.
I'm going on a trip for work
in a few days.
Where to?
Nanyu.
What for?
That place has nothing to do with us.
Lu's getting married, isn't he?
You call that a trip for work?
We didn't hold a wedding back then.
Now that he has invited me,
it would be impolite not to show up,
right?
Just think of it as a trip for work.
It wasn't I who didn't want a wedding.
Maybe you felt a bit uneasy.
Everyone said I was marrying up.
Was there
even a point of holding
a wedding?
Let me ask you then.
What about after my dad retired?
For so long, have you ever
taken me to dinner with your
schoolmates,
friends and colleagues,
or formally introduced me to them?
Are you worried about
being laughed at
now that my dad can't support you?
It was I who married up,
Deputy Court Pres. Yu.
Fang Haohao,
is this how you see me?
Xia Yingjie will be there too, right?
Perfect.
Revisit the town with her then.
I've noticed that recently...
Keep talking to me this way.
Neurotic, paranoid.
There'll be problems between us
sooner or later.
Things weren't like now when we
first got together.
I'm not going then.
When is the wedding?
The 8th.
[Nanyu County People's Court,
People's Procuratorate]
Judge Zhang,
thank you.
I had given up hope.
But the file
was surprisingly recovered.
This is what I thought at that time.
Even if the file had gone missing,
it couldn't have been just yours, right?
It's not like you are some big shot.
A large batch of files must have been
misplaced somewhere.
Fortunately,
a few days ago in town,
expired files were being disposed of.
So I looked through them.
I was just in luck.
Judge Zhang,
you gave me a second life.
It's been over ten years.
Get up.
More than a decade.
You're a grown man. Stop crying.
It's not like I've done nothing
but look for your file
over these ten-odd years.
Recovering this file
is only a start.
You need to do
the next steps yourself.
Find your former colleagues
and ask them for their testimonies.
They were the ones who falsely
accused me of cooking the books.
How could I ask them for help?
W-Will
this work?
Well,
then tell them straight
that the case has exceeded the statutory
limitation period
and cannot be retried.
Besides,
the books you handled back then
do not reflect
professionalism or completion.
Tell them not to
worry about legal liabilities.
Also, don't think about
seeking compensation.
All you should demand
is a statement so as to clear
your name.
Yes, exactly.
Just a statement.
I have nothing left in my life
but my innocence.
No need to see me out.
Hey, old bud.
Mentor!
Mentor.
It's you, Yizhong!
Give me a hug.
Mentor.
A hug, huh?
You're as strong as ever.
Yes, I'm doing great.
Judge Zhang.
I'm leaving then.
Take care.
Mentor, h-he's that...
Yes.
He drops by once a month.
Mentor has chatted with him
for ten-odd years.
He's aged quite a bit.
Almost all his hair's gone.
Look at me.
I'm in a much worse shape than him!
You're different.
You look younger this way.
Listen to him...
Good for you, kid.
You've learned to be cheesy too.
How have you been?
Things haven't been easy
in these ten-odd years, huh?
I've been learning.
But I do have regrets.
I wish I had understood earlier
the many things you told me.
I heard from Zeming about the case
you tried in Binjiang.
Yizhong, you should think it this way.
If that case
had been tried ten years ago
anywhere else,
the ruling would be a death sentence
all the same.
Fortunately, the legal system
is still improving.
Some costs
are inevitable.
It is difficult for an individual
to break through
the limitations of the times.
Do you get it?
Anyway,
we must look forward
and focus on the future.
I understand all that.
Yu has also told me they are
trying to figure something out,
seeing if the sentence could be
changed or reduced.
You see, just as I said,
justice delayed
is better than justice denied.
Lu Zeming!
Be careful.
Your father-in-law is looking for you.
I-Is he looking for me happily
or angrily?
Has he ever been happy?
Off you go!
-You...
-Just you go.
I-I'll have to take off.
Let's go.
To my office.